Camilo Peter Sarmiento

Atlanta, GA • Phone: 770-375-8615 • E-Mail: camsarm11@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/camilopsarmiento



Summary

UX Designer with 3+ years of product management experience. Delivered multiple releases for the UPS Global Customs Portal with enhancements that included 18+ additional languages, case management, and commodity charge details. Experience developing engaging user experiences in a team setting.

Skills

- A/B Testing
- User Interviews
- Usability Testing
- Information Architecture and Site Mapping
- Interaction Design
- Wireframes and Page Layout
- Prototyping

- Color Theory
- Sprint Planning
- Agile Methodology
- Figma
- Photoshop
- Invision
- HTML/CSS

Key Positions Held

Senior User Representative - UPS

4/2020 - Present

Alpharetta, GA 30004

- Engage with stakeholders to coordinate business and functional requirements for Next Generation Brokerage (Formerly known as TCIP).
- Interact with internal and external customers, teams, and associates.
- Deliver production support and end user training.
- Led Country Implementations for the UPS Global Customs Portal. Oversaw additions such as Entry Detail Enhancements, Case Management, Commodity, Declaration Charge Enhancements and PGA Statistics.

Marketing Special Assignment

2/2022 - 5/2022

- Communicated with region leads on Cross Border API integration process
- Created reports on brokerage holds, API activity, as well as Volume & Revenue.
- Created an internal training video on the UPS Cross Border API's as a Subject Matter Expert

Head of Instruction - Cornerstone Academic

8/2018 - 3/2020

Suwanee, GA 30024

- Taught SAT and ACT exam prep courses including Chemistry, Physics and Math
- Created curriculum for students.
- Communicated student progress to parents
- Accepted and processed billing information from clients.

- ❖ Administered Practice SAT, ACT and placements exams.
- Graded practice SAT and ACT exams.

Video Designer - Randstad - Alcon

2/2018 - 6/2018

Johns Creek, GA 30097

- Created training videos for new hire employees using cGMP's.
- Converted SOP documents into video format. Interviewed technicians to highlight issues with procedures.
- Organized company training video database. Filmed with Sony Professional Handycam and recorded voice overs with sound board and Rode Mic.
- Promoted company events through visual aids such as posters and display monitors. Photographer for the Johns Creek Campus.
- ❖ Managed Social Media advertisement for company events.
- Executed use of Adobe Premiere Pro, After Effects, Photoshop and Illustrator for content creation.

Graduate Researcher - Cornell University

8/2015 - 5/2017

Ithaca, NY 14853

- * Researched chemical structures in an organic chemistry lab.
- Used research methodology to record and analyze data. Presented findings weekly at group meetings.
- Organized lab's chemical inventory and procured new chemicals for inventory.
- Wrote and edited manuscripts and research proposals.
- Collaborated with group members to find the best method of gathering and analyzing data.

Training and Development

Georgia Institute of Technology – UX/UI Bootcamp Certificate

12/2022 - 6/2023

Atlanta, GA 30332

Hands-on training with user centric-design research, design thinking, visual prototyping and wire-framing, interface design, storyboarding, visual design theory, web prototyping with HTML5 and CSS, interaction design with JavaScript and jQuery.

Education

Cornell University – Additional Coursework

8/2015 - 5/2017

Ithaca, NY 14853

Cornell University Chemistry PhD Program. Completed Master's coursework and graduate research with David B. Collum. Courses covered organic synthesis, polymer chemistry, physical organic chemistry, and analytical chemistry. Took a Mathematical Methods course involving Python.

University of Georgia – B.S. Chemistry GPA: 3.76

8/2011 - 5/2015

Athens, GA 30609

Bachelor of Science in Chemistry. Graduated Magna Cum Laude with a minor in Physics. Undergraduate research with Jason Locklin. Research Title: Synthesis and characterization of self-assembled monolayers on gold and indium tin oxide surfaces.